De la Torre Family Papers, 1874-2003 (bulk: 1910-1946)
Special Collections at the University of Arizona Libraries
De la Torre Family Papers, 1874-2003
MS 420
De la Torre Family
Papers, 1874-2003 (bulk: 1910-1946). This collection contains material documenting the De la Torre family and their involvement in the Cristero Movement. The family traveled from central Mexico to Nogales, Sonora bringing the Movement to northern Mexico. Items include biographical materials; correspondence; printed materials, including pamphlets, newsletters, newsclippings, and Public Statements; and photographs and negatives. The bulk of the material is printed materials and photographs. This collection also contains over 280 books that can be found in the University of Arizona Library catalog under the title Cristero Movement Collection. The majority of the material is in Spanish. Una version en de esta guia de colección está disponible.
Processing note: Material received from Jose De la Torre in 2014 was processed as an addition in 2015. The finding aid was revised to include the addition of manuscripts and photographs as a new series.
12.50 linear feet
Special Collections at the University of Arizona Libraries University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
The Cristero Movement (1926-1929) was a revolt by Catholics against the Mexican government that occurred in response to anti-Catholic legislation. This legislation began with the 1917 Constitution of Mexico but it was not until the presidency of Plutarco Calles (1924-1928) that these laws were enforced. President Calles added his own strict legislation severely restricting the clergy and Church in Mexico. The Cristero Movement originated in southern Mexico and moved north. The Movement lasted a decade and claimed over 100,000 lives. The Cristeros eventually achieved religious freedom in practice. Anti-clerical provisions remain a part of the Constitution but are unenforced. The De la Torre family, who had close ties to the Catholic Church and clergy, was instrumental in bringing the Cristero Movement to northern Mexico. The family, originally from Zacatecas and Guanajuato, moved to Aguascalientes and then in 1922 to San Luis Potosí. The family moved again to Tampico for economic reasons and finally to Nogales, both Sonora and Arizona, to escape persecution from authorities because of their involvement in the Church and Movement.
Ignacio De la Torre Berumen (b. 1878) and María De la Torre Uribarren (Velasco) (b. 1878) were the parents of eight children, many of whom were important figures within the Movement, both as priests and secular members. María (b. 1900) was a central support figure for the family and served as a point of communication and information. María's boyfriend, Fidel Muro, who was also involved in the Movement, was captured and executed in 1928. Ignacio (b. 1901) was a priest who became the vicar general of the Archdiocese of Hermosillo. He was active in education and founded several religious organizations. He was murdered in 1979 in Imuris, Sonora under mysterious circumstances. Both Francisco (b. 1905) and Carlos (b. 1914) became respected Jesuit priests. These three brothers were instrumental in reopening churches the government closed in Nogales. Alfonso (b. 1908), a Cristero soldier, was killed during fighting near Agua Caliente near the town of Suaqui de Batuc in 1935. Luis (b. 1910) was also involved in the Cristero Movement and later married. Neither Edmundo (b.1912) nor Benjamín (b.1918) were heavily involved in the Movement but focused instead on family and business.
The De la Torre family was acquainted with prominent figures of the Cristero Movement such as the priest Juan Navarrete. Several members of the family belonged to the Cristero organizations Asociación Católica de la Juventud Mexicana (ACJM) and the Liga Nacional Defensora de la Libertad (LNDL). Both María and Ignacio sometimes used pseudonyms in their correspondence and publications. María used the pseudonym Margarita Sofia and Ignacio used the pseudonyms Jose, Ysidro, Ismael Gomez, and Ismael Tizcareño.
Organization
This collection is organized into 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Files, 1874-1984
Series 2: Correspondence, 1890-1994
Series 3: Subject Files, 1928-1944
Series 4: Printed Materials, 1885-1990
Series 5: Photographs and Negatives, 1874-1970
Series 6: Oversize Materials, 1906-1979
Series 7: Addition of Manuscripts and Family Photographs, 1910-2003
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1874-2003 (bulk: 1910-1946). This collection contains the papers of the De la Torre family documenting their involvement in the Cristero Movement and their move from Central Mexico to Sonora including Nogales. The bulk of the collection consists of printed materials and photographs. The printed materials highlight the progress of the Movement and include religious and political pamphlets, newsletters, newsclippings, and Public Statements. The majority of photographs relate to the De la Torre family and friends. Some materials relate to Cristero political organizations such as Asociación Católica de la Juventud Mexicana (ACJM) and the Liga Nacional Defensora de la Libertad (LNDL) including a financial ledger and administrative documents. Other unique materials include a combat log, personal accounts, and political cartoons. Also included are the personal papers and correspondence of the de la Torre family. The majority of the material is in Spanish. This collection also contains over 280 books that can be found in the University of Arizona Library catalog under the title Cristero Movement Collection.
Related Material
Juan Navarrete y Guerrero Collection, (1912-2000), MS 423
La version en de esta guia de colección está disponible.
Access Terms
De la Torre Family - Archives.
Cristero Rebellion, 1926-1929.
Cristero Rebellion, 1926-1929 -- Religous aspects.
Church and state -- Mexico -- History -- 20th century.
Mexico, North--Politics and government--20th century.
Sonora (Mexico: State).
Navarrete y Guerrero, Juan, 1886-1982.
Asociación Católica de la Juventud Mexicana.
Liga Nacional Defensora de la Libertad Religiosa (Mexico).
Container List
- Biographical Files. 1874-1984
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains biographical materials relating to the members of the De la Torre family such as yearbooks, birth, communion, marriage and death announcements, a family tree, immigration documents, family histories, personal accounts, and certificates. Also included are materials on other religious leaders. Most biographical materials are in Spanish. Note: Some materials are located in Series 6: Oversize Materials.
  - Certificates. undated, 1877-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - De la Torre, Alfonso - Death. 1935-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - De la Torre, Benjamín. undated, 1926-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - De la Torre, Carlos. undated, 1914-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - De la Torre, Carlos - Yearbooks. 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - De la Torre, Carlos - Yearbooks. 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - De la Torre, Edmundo. 1912-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - De la Torre, Francisco. undated, 1918-1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - De la Torre, Ignacio. undated, 1909-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - De la Torre, Ignacio - Yearbook. 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - De la Torre, Luis. undated, 1910-1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - De la Torre Berumen, Ignacio - Death. 1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - De la Torre Family History - Estampas Cristeras. undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - De la Torre Family History - Family Tree. undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Duval, Louis. undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Funeral Announcements. undated, 1885-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General. undated, 1874-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Immigration Documents. 1927-1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Muro, Fidel. 1928-1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Navarrete, Juan. undated, 1920-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Uribarren De la Torre, María. undated, 1887-1927 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence. 1890-1994
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains correspondence mostly between De la Torre family members but also among the Archbishop of Hermosillo Juan Navarrete and other figures of the Cristero movement. Most correspondence is in Spanish. Some correspondence is in English and Latin.
  - De la Torre, Alfonso. undated, 1921-1928 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - De la Torre, Alfonso. 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - De la Torre, Alfonso - Death. 1935-1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - De la Torre, Benjamín. undated, 1931-1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - De la Torre, Benjamín. 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - De la Torre, Carlos. undated, 1926-1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - De la Torre, Benjamin. 1939-1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - De la Torre, Edmundo. undated, 1917-1964 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - De la Torre, Francisco. undated, 1920-1929 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - De la Torre, Francisco. 1930-1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - De la Torre, Francisco. 1940-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - De la Torre, Ignacio. undated, 1919-1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - De la Torre, Ignacio. 1935-1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - De la Torre, Luis. 1921-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - De la Torre, María. 1909-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - De la Torre, María - Biographical Sketch of Fidel Muro. 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - De la Torre Berumen, Ignacio. 1900-1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Duval, Louis. undated, 1930-1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General. undated, 1917-1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - López, Eulalio. 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Manríquez y Zarate, José de Jesús. 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Muro Family. undated, 1927-1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Navarrete, Juan. 1919-1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Palomar y Vizcarra, Miguel. 1944-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Unión Nacional Sinarquista. 1937-1944 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Uribarren De la Torre, María. undated, 1890-1945 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Subject Files. 1928-1967
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains material relating to the Cristero Movement including a memoir, financial ledger, printed money and a combat log. Also included are other miscellaneous materials such as yearbooks, stamps and documents relating to Germany circa World War II. Most of the materials are in Spanish.
  - Address Book. undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Cartoons - Alfonso De la Torre. undated, 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Colegio Centro América - Yearbook. 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Combat Log. 1932 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Financial Ledger. 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - German Documents. undated, 1936-1945 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Gregorian University (Rome, Italy). undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Liga Nacional Defensora de la Libertad - Memoir. 1937 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Maps. undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Money. undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Pro, Miguel (Father). undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Religious Cards. undated, 1935-1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Seminario Nacional Mexicano - Montezuma, New Mexico - Pontifical Yearbook. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Stamps. undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Printed Materials. 1885-1990
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains political/religious documents mostly concerning the Cristero Movement including propaganda, pamphlets, newsletters, fliers, and newsclippings. Also included are souvenirs and other religious materials. Most materials are in Spanish and others are in English, French, German, and Latin. Note: Some materials are located in Series 6: Oversize Materials.
  - Brochures. undated, 1931-1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Flyers. undated, 1914-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hymns. undated, 1924-1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Journals - General. 1904-1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Journals - Juventud Católica. 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Journals - Juventud Católica. 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Magazines - General. 1924-1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Magazines - Juan Diego. 1935-1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Magazines - Juventud. 1939-1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Magazines - Latinoamérica. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Magazines - Legión. 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Magazines - Legión. 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Magazines - Señal. 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Magazines - Revista Católica. 1929 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Magazines - Unión. 1945-1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous. undated, 1904-1927 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous. 1945-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Newsclippings. undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Newsclippings. 1894-1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters - El Auxilio Mariano. 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters - La Batea. 1928 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters - Boletín de la Comisión Central de Instrucción Religiosa de la Acción Católica Mexicana. 1933 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters - Boletín de la Guerra. undated, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters - Boletín de la Sociedad de Santa Teresita. 1928-1935 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters - Boletín Oficial de Integrismo. 1952 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Newsletters - Boletín Oficial del IV Centrario Guadalupano. 1931 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Newsletters - Buenas Nuevas. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Newsletters - Carta Pastoral. undated, 1923-1936 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Newsletters - Carta Pastoral. 1938-1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters - Comite Popular de Defensa Mexicana. 1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters - Criterio. 1926-1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters - Criterio. 1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters - Cultura Cristiana. 1933-1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters - De Broma y de Vera. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters - David. 1937-1959 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters - Desde México. undated, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters - Desde Mi Destierro. undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters - Desde Mi Sotano. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters - El Ensayo. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters - Evangelio. 1945 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters - El Faro. 1932 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters - General. undated, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters - Gladius. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters - Hector. undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters - Hoja Parroquial. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters - La Honda. 1936 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters - Juan Diego. 1940 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters - La Lucha. 1935 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters - Las Maravillas del Santo Rosario. 1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters - Liga Nacional Defensora de la Libertad Religiosa. undated, 1926-1936 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters - Minutillo. 1929 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters - Nuestra Vida. 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters - Onir. 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Newsletters - Organo Oficial del Comite Popular de Defensa Mexicana. 1935 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Newsletters - Para Nuestros Amigos. 1952 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Newsletters - Pro Patria. 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Newsletters - Pro Patria. 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Newsletters - Propaganda Misional. 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Newsletters - El Propagandista Católico. 1928 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Newsletters - Reconquista. 1930-1944 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Newsletters - Regis/El Heraldo del Hogar. 1933 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Newsletters - Saber. 1935 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Newsletters - El Sembrador. undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Newsletters - Sembrando. 1953 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Newsletters - La Trinchera. 1936 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Newsletters - La Unión. 1933 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Newsletters - Vida del Alma. 1953 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Newsletters - La Voz Guadalupana. 1942 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Newsletters - Ydea al Servicio de la Verdad. 1953 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Pamphlets. undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Pamphlets. 1885-1920 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Pamphlets. 1922-1925 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Pamphlets. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Pamphlets. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Pamphlets. 1928-1934 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Pamphlets. 1935 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets. 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets. 1943-1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets. 1969-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Plays. undated, 1894-1906 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Plays. 1919-1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Poems. undated, 1905-1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Programs. undated, 1910-1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Public Statements. undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Public Statements. 1914-1925 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Public Statements. 1926 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Public Statements. 1927-1933 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Public Statements. 1934-1936 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Public Statements. 1937-1939 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Public Statements. 1940-1971 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Photographs and Negatives. 1874-1970
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains photographs and negatives primarily of the De la Torre family. Also included are other friends and relatives. Some photographers and studios included in this collection are Leopoldo Varela, Jose M. M. Aguilar, Foto Harrison and Linder Art Studio. There are also single photographs from C.B. Waite and Govan and North. Locations of studios and photographers include Aguascalientes, Guadalajara, Navajoa, Sonora, Nogales, Sonora and Arizona, San Luis Potosí, and Zacatecas. Most photograph captions are in Spanish. Note: Some materials are located in Series VI: Oversize Materials.
  - Compact Disc - Copia de Archivo Familiar De la Torre Uribarren undate (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Folder contains a detailed inventory of the compact disc
  - Photographs - Aguascalientes Group. undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photographs - California. undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Photographs - Campa Family. 1883-1907 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - Catholic Family League (Aguascalientes). undated, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - Churches. undated, 1885-1927 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - Coronación de la Virgen Santísima de Guadalupe (Los Angeles, California). 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Cristero Soldiers. undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Alfonso. undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Alfonso. 1910-1936 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Alfonso - Exhumation of body. 1944 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Benjamín. undated, 1926-1953 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Carlos. undated, 1931-1961 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Edmundo. undated, 1938-1953 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Francisco. undated, 1920-1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Ignacio. undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Ignacio. 1920-1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Ignacio - Travels. undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, Luis. undated, 1921-1956 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Photographs - De la Torre, María. undated, 1901-1948 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Photographs - De la Torre Berumen, Ignacio. undated, 1896-1948 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Photographs - De la Torre Berumen, Ignacio and Uribarren De la Torre, María. undated, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Photographs - De la Torre Berumen Family. undated, 1874-1901 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Photographs - De la Torre Family. undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Photographs - De la Torre Family. 1906-1936 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Photographs - De la Torre Family Photoalbum. undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Photographs - Delgado Family. undated, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - Downing Family. undated, 1944-1947 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - Duval, Louis. undated, 1932-1938 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Photographs - Eucharist Crusade. 1924 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Photographs - Garibi Family. undated, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - Garibi y Velasco Family. undated, 1909-1920 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Photographs - General. undated (Box 7, Folder 7-11)
  - Photographs - General. 1891-1899 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - General. 1901-1919 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Photographs - General. 1920-1929 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Photographs - General. 1930-1939 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Photographs - General. 1940-1970 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Photographs - Gabral Family. undated, 1891-1938 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Photographs - Iglesia y Virgen. undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Photographs - Mercado Family. undated, 1931-1941 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Photographs - Muro, Fidel. undated, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Photographs - Navarrete, Juan. undated, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Photographs - Noriega, Alfonso. undated, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Photographs - Orozco y Velasco. undated, 1910-1914 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Photographs - San Pedro de la Cueoa. undated, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Photographs - Serafico College. undated, 1922-1929 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Photographs - Sinarquistas Movement. undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Photographs - Sonoran Church. undated, 1927-1970 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Photographs - Southern Cristero Families. undated, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Photographs - Tumacacori National Monument (Tumacacori, Arizona). undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Photographs - Uribarren De la Torre, María. undated, 1897-1901 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Photographs - Uribarren Family. undated, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Photographs - Velazco de Perez. undated, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Photographs - Velazco Family. undated, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Photographs - Villegas de Noriega Family. 1906 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Photographs - Ysleta College. undated, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Negatives - Buena Vista University. undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Negatives - Churches. undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Negatives - Cristero Soldiers. undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Negatives - De la Torre, Alfonso. undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Negatives - De la Torre, Alfonso - Exhumation of body. 1944 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Negatives - De la Torre, Benjamín. undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Negatives - De la Torre, Carlos. undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Negatives - De la Torre, Ignacio. undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Negatives - De la Torre, Luis. undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Negatives - De la Torre, María. undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Negatives - De la Torre Berumen, Ignacio. undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Negatives - De la Torre Family. undated (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Negatives - General. undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Negatives - Iglesia y Virgen. undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Negatives - Muro, Fidel. undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Negatives - Nogales. undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Negatives - Uribarren De la Torre, María. undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Oversize Materials. 1906-1979
  This series contains oversize items from various series including biographical files, printed materials and photographs and negatives.
  - Biographical Files: Certificates. 1929 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials: Magazines - General. 1939-1952 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials: Magazines - The Homeless Child. 1929-1939 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials: Newsletters - General. undated, 1929-1936 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Printed Materials: Newspapers. 1923-1933 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Printed Materials: Newspapers. 1934-1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Printed Materials: Posters. undated, 1924-1974 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Printed Materials: Public Statements. undated, 1924-1961 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photographs and Negatives: Photographs - Churches. undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Photographs and Negatives: Photographs - De la Torre, Alfonso. undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Photographs and Negatives: Photographs - De la Torre, Benjamín. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Photographs and Negatives: Photographs - De la Torre, Luis. 1942 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Photographs and Negatives: Photographs - De la Torre Berumen, Ignacio and De la Torre Uribarren, María. undated (Box 10, Folder 8)